Ong Guo Xiang

Email: ong.guoxiang@gmail.com LinkedIn: <u>www.linkedin.com/in/ongguoxiang</u>

Location:SingaporeGithub:https://github.com/gxitePhone:+65 9177 7675Portfolio:https://gxite.github.io

I am currently a Research Assistant at the National University of Singapore, Department of Architecture. Prior to this, I had spent 2 years working as a junior architect in Singapore, taking on both project management and design roles.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant

National University of Singapore

Jul 2019 - Present

Project: Measuring Physical Profile and Use of Park Connector Network with Deep Learning and Multi-Source Multi-Modal Data Analytics

- Responsible for setting up and maintaining the software and hardware environment to perform object and action detections using Machine Learning models.
- Adapted python scripts from an open sourced research on real time action detections, to work on large numbers of simultaneous detection on long GoPro videos.
- Wrote python scripts to process to the resulting detections for analysis within ArcGIS.
- Responsible for documenting all research related data and methodologies.

Architectural Associate

DCA Architects Pte Ltd

Jun 2017 - Jun 2019

- Worked as a Design Architect in collaboration with local consultant teams in Vietnam for the design of a condominium complex and show gallery in Ho Chi Minh City. Main contributions includes the design of auxiliary facilities, facades and the show gallery. Responsible for generating building renders and visuals for all client presentations.
- Worked as a Project Architect for 2 Addition and Alteration works.
 Main responsibilities includes administrating the construction contracts, obtaining clearances from regulatory agencies, reviewing shop drawings, provide design directions and visuals for presentations.
- Worked on developing computational design workflows within Rhinoceros 3D + Grasshopper and Revit + Dynamo. Contributions includes:
 - A simple pipeline to generate customised perforated panels within Rhinoceros 3D.
 - An experimental workflow that enables massing model within Revit to be automatically generated based on inputs from an Excel sheet.

SKILLS

CAD & Modelling

Rhinoceros 3D (proficient)
Grasshopper (proficient)
AutoCAD (proficient)
Sketchup (proficient)
Revit (prior exp)
Dynamo (prior exp)

Graphics & Rendering

Photoshop (proficient)
Illustrator (proficient)
InDesign (proficient)
Lumion (proficient)
Vray (prior exp)

Programming Languages

Python (proficient)
C++ (basic proficiency)
Java (prior exp)

LANGUAGES

English (Professional) Mandarin (Mother Tongue)

EDUCATION

National University of Singapore

- Master of Arts, Architecture (2016-2017)
- Bachelor of Arts (Hons. Distinction), Architecture (2012-2016)

.